# John Vincent A. Lanticse

A curious Computer Engineer well-versed in Server Management and Software Engineering in Mobile, Backend and Frontend development with 8 years of industry experience. Seeking to further grow, learn and apply his technical and professional expertise.

**EXPERIENCE** 

**Go Team** (1 year 6 months)

il Building Jose Ma. del Mar, IT Park Apas, Cebu City

## Senior Software Engineer

November 2023 - Present **Job Summary**:

 Laid the foundation to a Payment Processing platform from gathering requirements, designing processes and infrastructure, implementation with Ruby on Rails and deployment to Amazon Web Services

## Cloudstaff Modern Workforce Inc. (1 year 4 months)

Ayala Center Cebu Tower, Bohol St., Cebu City, 6000 Cebu

## **Senior Software Engineer**

July 2022 - November 2023 **Job Summary**:

 client engaged as Ruby on Rails developer contributing to the development of product services for an E-learning platform and improving code quality and test coverage.

## **Koda Kollectiv** (5 years, 1 month)

A. S. Fortuna St, Mandaue City, 6014 Cebu

## **Junior Software Architect**

June 2020 - July 2022 (2 years, 1 month) **Job Summary**:

- assist in doing project estimates, designing architecture, research and planning.
- help in checking out technologies and setting up remote servers, writing scripts to improve its monitoring and administration.
- continue development and maintenance of client projects in native iOS and android development and Web/Api development using Ruby on Rails, AngularJs or React.

## **Software Engineer**

December 2019 - June 2020 (6 months) **Iob Summary**:

- develop a React application integrating Stripe and Azure.
- maintenance of Android and Angular applications.

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

June 2017 - December 2019 (2 year, 7 month) **Job Summary**:

- creates native Android versions of iOS applications.
- continues development of Android applications and Ruby on Rails APIs, integrating Push Notifications, Billing Api, Messaging, Firebase services.
- maintenance of AngularJS web GUI to manage devices.
- creation of chrome extensions integrated with Ruby on Rails Admin & Api and Google Sheets & AppScript.
- integration of printers to a POS system

#### Awards:

- Most Project Award (2018) for being a project MVP and having a hand at bringing to fruition numerous projects
- Reporting Wizard Award (2018) for being an employee who is great at reporting to his managers and giving great updates for the benefit of his managers

Address: **Catang, Argao, Cebu, Ph** E-mail: **jv.lanticse@gmail.com** 

Github: ctrlshiftjv

Linkedin: **John Vincent Lanticse**Website: **wiki.ctrlshiftjv.dev** 

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Mathematics University of San Carlos Nasipit, Talamban, Cebu City

August 2018 - December 2022

## Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

University of San Carlos Nasipit, Talamban, Cebu City

June 2013 - April 2018

#### **BACKEND RELATED SKILLS**

Ruby on Rails (8+ years),

Spring Boot (< 1 year),

PostgreSQL (5+ years),

Ubuntu VPS (8+ years),

Nginx (3+ years),

MySQL (2+ years),

AWS (2+ years),

## FRONTEND RELATED SKILLS

React (1+ years)

Angular (2+ years)

HTML, CSS, JavaScript (7+ years)

#### **MOBILE RELATED SKILLS**

Android (1+ years)

**iOS** (< 1 year)

Flutter (< 1 year)